# EMMANUEL DALYOP

## **Frontend Developer**

#### **Emmanuel Dalyop**

Abuja-keffi Rd Masaka, Nasarawa state, Nigeria.

(+234) 705 1242 451 emmanueldcode@gmail.com https://ecodejr.netlify.app

#### **Career Objective**

Responsible student with good judgment, a flexible schedule, a hard worker experienced in problem-solving service and time management, a dedicated worker with excellent communication, and computer skills. Aiming to leverage my abilities to successfully fill the vacancy at your company. Frequently praised as hardworking by my peers, I can be relied upon to help your company achieve its goals.

#### **Experience**

#### SPUTNIK / Software Engineer (intern)

FEBRUARY 2022 - PRESENT. Area 1 ABUJA. NIGERIA

- Responsible for front and backend development.
- Responded to user email inquiries, and set up automated systems to send responses
- Documented test plans, testing procedures or test results.
- Recommended and implemented performance improvement updates
- Analyzed user needs to determine technical requirementsPerformed and directed Web site updates,
- Communicated with network personnel and Web site hosted agencies to address hardware and software issues affecting Web sites.
- Made sure user experience is always perfect.
- Worked with languages like: HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, REACT, PHP, PYTHON, GO, REACT, MYSQL

#### Federal Ministry of Interior / Tech assistant (intern)

October 2018 - MARCH 2019, Area 1 ABUJA, NIGERIA

- Responsible for maintenance of LAN connection
- Maintenance of Hardware/Software
- Data entry using MS word/MS Excel

**Education** 

#### FEDERAL POLYTECHNIC NASARAWA / National Diploma (ND)

SEPTEMBER 2018 - DECEMBER 2019, NIGERIA

• COMPUTER SCIENCE

### FEDERAL POLYTECHNIC NASARAWA / Higher National

**Diploma** 

SEPTEMBER 2022 - CURRENT, NIGERIA

• COMPUTER SCIENCE

**Skills** 

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JAVASCRIPT
- PYTHON
- PHP
- REACT
- NODEJS
- MYSQL

**Extracurricular Activities** 

- Table tennis
- Piano
- Gaming.

**Additional Skills** 

- SEO
- Graphics design
- Smart contracts